I've made up my mind to march
into the Shaderan house,
in order to face my parents
and to ascertain the truth.
I have an urgent message for Baron Shaderan!
Please open the gate!
If you don't, something terrible will happen!
What's impossible is impossible!
Now go on and leave!
Actually, haven't I seen
you somewhere before?
You're imagining things!
What's more important right now
is that you open this gate!
Marie, you're really certain about this?
I don't want to!
Open the gate! Open it right now!
Yes. Don't hold back.
No! I won't do it!
All right.
Open the gate!
If they won't open up, then we'll just
have to force our way through, right?
How many times do I have
to tell you? Enough is—
Punch through, Ringomaru!
You have a terrible taste in names!
I-I did try to tell her.
Episode 12 "It's Time to Settle This"
Mio.
Understood.
Wh-What are you doing? Stop it!
Let go of me!
I-Is she really a maid?
He wouldn't stop making a fuss, so I
took the liberty of restraining him.
What is all this? What do
you think you're doing?
I've been wanting to see you, Baron Shaderan.
Or rather... Father.
I've brought the baroness and their son.
It's been a while, hasn't it?
Father. Mother.
Big Sis Marie?
Cedric!
It seems that no one in your family
has realized who you are.
Well, when you came to the workshop,
you believed I was a boy, didn't you?
Now that you mention it, I did!
But why disguise yourself again?
I have to see it with my own eyes...
to make certain that the same
mistakes never happen again.
Marie! What do you think you're doing?
You didn't reply about the betrothal
ceremony no matter how long we waited,
so we came to see you in person.
We hoped that you would give
our love your approval.
If you do not believe
that we love each other,
then I'd like you to look at these.
It's a record in which I've written
exactly how much I love Marie.
Lord Kyros...
Is that man really all right?
No, he's too far gone.
I-In any case, I'd like
to have a proper talk.
Let's go to the hall.
My father and mother...
What will happen to them?
It's all right. Don't worry.
Trust your big sisters.
Big sisters?
Oh! Um... Just don't worry, all right?
All right.
It isn't likely that they'll see
through my sister's disguise.
Are you all right?
Y-Yes.
This is all so sudden, it's
made me feel a little ill.
Wh-Why is this servant here?
What sinister red hair!
The same cursed hair as Marie!
Baroness, that is an old superstition.
It's no superstition!
Because of Marie, both Lady
Sasha and Anastasia died!
So why is Marie the only one...
They looked like princesses!
Both Lady Sasha and Anastasia
were far more worthy, and yet...
Mother, your hair...
Don't trouble yourself over me!
Please just leave me alone!
How dare you treat me with such disrespect!
You really are born of
barbarians, aren't you?
I have nothing to discuss with you!
Hurry up and leave!
Please don't run away, Father.
R-Run away? Just who do you
think you're talking to?
I am the lord of this land and your father!
Lord of the land? A father?
Don't make me laugh.
What did you say? You—
Baron Shaderan, this is a written notice of
the stripping of your authority as a lord.
You can't speak Flarian, which is essential
for managing your lands, can you?
Wh-What are you talking about?
I just hate foreign languages, that's all!
In that case, please say
something in Flarian.
A simple conversation will do.
Th-That's...
After Sasha Shaderan passed away,
you failed to officially inform the crown
that you had your daughter Marie act in
your stead. We've already investigated it.
Gregor Shaderan, we cannot entrust the
lives of our precious citizens to you.
For abandoning your
official duties as a lord,
and the crime of covering it up,
you will pay dearly.
A-Am I... going to lose everything?
No.
There is one way to preserve the barony.
Although the Granado family
will essentially take over,
you would retain your title and residence.
Talented personnel will be dispatched here.
However, there is one condition.
A condition?
Please apologize to me.
For violating her dignity, brainwashing
her, and tying her down to this house...
If you apologize for these inhumane acts and
ask for help, then I promise you assistance.
All of us here discussed it,
and that is what we decided.
Father, please give me your answer.
Why didn't you follow the proper procedures?
Why force everything on me instead?
S-Stop whining!
It's only natural for a good-for-nothing
daughter to obey her parents!
Not only do you show no gratitude towards
Marie, even now, you take that attitude?
As a fellow noble, let me say one thing.
To apologize.
To seek help. To feel gratitude.
Each of those things are essential in a lord.
If there's something you can't do, then
ask for help and rely on someone else.
If you show your gratitude properly,
then there is no embarrassment or crime.
The true crime is to protect one's
own pride by turning truth into lies,
and to hold others in contempt.
That egocentrism is the crime.
The previous baroness, Sasha, hoped for
your growth as a lord here, didn't she?
Stop talking!
What do you know?
Mother... My mother...
never expected anything from me!
So that's it!
You wanted Lady Sasha to
have high hopes for you.
I-I... I...
That's enough! Are you happy
destroying your own house?
Just how much misfortune must you
bring us before you're satisfied?
That red hair will bring
unhappiness to everyone!
Lady Sasha and my darling
Anastasia... you killed them both!
Now, look here.
I'm sorry to tell you, but I'm not dead.
Anastasia?
Could you please not blame Marie for
all these bizarre offenses you see?
And really, I guess my blonde
hair was all you ever saw in me.
You've come back to me, my Anastasia!
Oh, this blonde hair!
It's so beautiful! My princess!
Stop it.
Let go of me!
Mama, I have never once been your Anastasia.
Mother. As I thought...
Hair... My hair!
Sh-She has red hair?
It seems that the baron knew.
To look down on Marie like that when
her own hair is the same color...
Marie cannot possibly find happiness!
She has the same red hair as me!
She isn't like Lady Sasha and Anastasia!
I finally understand.
Mother, you wanted to believe, didn't you?
Marie... What do you mean?
Mother, for you, to be like
Grandmother and Anastasia,
ladies with small builds and beautiful
blonde hair, was essential for being a "princess."
You must admire and envy them so much.
And that's why you wanted to believe...
believe that women like us, with our
red hair and our height, meet with misfortune...
That it's inevitable.
Stop talking.
Stop talking! Stop talking! Stop talking!
What can you possibly know?
Someone with red hair can never be happy!
They can never become a princess!
Even Lady Sasha never loved me!
That is how it has always been for me!
I always rejected myself as well.
I thought that no one could ever love me,
and so I closed off my heart.
But...
after meeting Lord Kyros and everyone at the
castle, I've finally realized something.
That I lacked courage...
the courage to face myself.
Lord Kyros, and you, too, Mio...
and everyone from the
castle who isn't here...
I am truly sorry for leading you around and
hurting you with my baseless assumptions.
Marie.
Mother...
I want to walk into the future with Lord
Kyros and everyone at Granado Castle.
So let's put an end to this now.
A-Anastasia! You, you are
the one person who always...
Mama... no. Elvira Shaderan,
Marie and I are not your dolls.
Please don't keep us tied down any longer.
In the end, the House of Granado
took control of the Shaderan lands.
In order to return and become the next lord,
Cedric is studying hard at a school in the capital.
And Father is attending the same school as
Cedric, taking a gruelingly strict course.
If he manages to graduate, he'll
be allowed to become Cedric's valet
Lord
Son's
Valet
and return to the Shaderan lands.
His future seems likely to
be filled with difficulty.
Still, that baron certainly
seems to be working hard.
Well, he found Lady Sasha's
journal in a storehouse.
Journal?
Yes.
Apparently, she'd written down her
feelings about the baron and his wife.
I'm sure it must have given
him something to think about.
Mother was exempt from
any legal consequences,
but now she lives in that
empty house all alone.
If you can't open the door, then
how about going in through a window?
Stop being silly. I'm grateful that you
gave me a ride on your horse, but...
You're no fun. I know you'd feel
forlorn if you were all alone.
Th-That's not...
No, the truth is, I'm so anxious
I don't know what to do.
I've been lying to Old Man Norman
ever since I first met him.
I'm Arthur! You got a problem with that?
Asking him to allow me to continue working
with him would be entirely too selfish.
You cast aside a life of
being treated like a doll,
and grabbed the chance of a life
doing what you like, didn't you?
In that case, you have to have courage!
I'm always on the side
of people who work hard.
Now, go on!
W-Wait!
Old Man Norman...
Um, I...
The count told me everything.
I hear your name isn't
Arthur, it's Anastasia.
Yes.
What? These are...
Yours.
I've ordered hammers and gloves.
Honestly...
I'll have to change all the
tools to suit your hands.
You should've told me the truth
sooner, my idiot apprentice.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry!
Thank you!
Good. Very good.
Now, shall we go, Ringomaru?
And so the height of summer arrived.
Today...
I become the future bride
of the person I love.
This is delicious!
And the plating is beautiful!
Toppo's cooking is the best in the world!
I recommend the special apple pie as well!
Oh, how lovely!
It's because I had such
good material to work with!
You see? If we do this here...
Oh, how modern!
By the way,
this hair oil can be ordered through
the Granado Trading Company in the capital!
My, this looks magnificent!
It isn't just looks!
It's also extremely practical!
Marie is so beautiful!
I wish someone would be my
escort like that sometime.
Princess?
Please, take my hand!
Will you come and dance with me?
Yes!
I have waited so impatiently for this day.
My lady! Master!
You look beautiful, Marie!
Come now. You are just as beautiful!
Ugh, you again?
I like it!
That honesty of yours that doesn't
hesitate even in the face of royalty.
You're a type I've never met before.
Say, would you like to
give being my wife a try?
Sure.
What?
What's wrong? The betrothal's
set now, isn't it?
A-Actually, the thing is, I already have
five fiancées that I've never seen before.
Is that so?
Hey! I do happen to be a prince, you know?
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I have no time to look
after a grumbling prince.
I was worried about what might happen,
but we've made it to this day safely.
I never imagined I'd be able to
see my son shining like this.
It must be because you raised
him with love, Lady Liu Liu.
No, it's thanks to you, Mio.
What?
You stayed beside the two of them
and supported them. Thank you.
So, as the person who had to look
after them, what do you think?
Do you think they'll make
a good married couple?
I'm not sure.
Both of them are still developing, and the
master is currently at the height of puberty.
Stop it! You shouldn't
tell the truth like that.
However, I'm certain that
a happy future awaits them.
As to whether it seems believable or not...
the faces of everyone here at the
castle say it all, don't they?
Lord Kyros.
Marie, what's wrong?
Nothing. I was just remembering.
Remembering everything from
the day I met you until today.
When I think about it, we spent most of the
time on different pages from each other.
That day, when I met you,
my whole world changed.
You are the first person I ever truly wanted.
Marie, for being born, for
being at my side... thank you.
No, I'm the one who should thank you.
That day, light shone into
my closed off little world.
Green eyes more beautiful than any
star brought color into my world.
When I hesitated, you took my
hand and moved forward with me.
Things I'd forgotten... Things
I learned for the first time...
Every single one of them created
the "us" that we are now.
We will find happiness.
As long as we're by each other's sides.
Translation: Elanor Sakamoto
Subtitle Timing: Edgar Cruz
Editing and Typesetting: Ashley Barboza
Quality Control: S. Bilyeu
Translation Check: Michelle Tymon